So, let's now define these datatypes in Isabelle as a demo again. So, I will start with the natural numbers.
I will just say a datatype. The notation here is very similar to what I used in the virtual backboard.
So, a natural number is either a zero, which is the first constructor, or a successor, which is the second constructor, and that takes another natural number, right?
So, then now we have a term. So, for example, a zero can be represented like that. A two can be represented like that, and so on and so forth.
A second datatype is lists, which we discussed also. So, this is a list that takes an A, alpha. It has two constructors as well.
So, either nil or successor. I will just call this cons, but just double S so that we don't confuse it with the list that is defined by default in Isabelle.
Isabelle, again, takes an element and another list. And again, if you want to represent a list that is an empty list, then we just say nil.
I will just call this also nil with a double L so that it's not confused with the nil, which is defined by default in Isabelle, and then a list that has, for example, two and three in it.
So, I will just say cons, and that's cons three, which is consed with the empty list.
So, as you can see here, that is the algebraic representation of the alpha list of two elements. Now, let's do the tree, which we did.
So, an alpha tree, again, is either a leaf or an internal node that has a left subtree and an element content and a right subtree.
And to represent, for example, our example tree from the virtual blackboard, to represent that algebraically here, we just say it's going to be a bit of work, but maybe I'll just represent a tree that has just as root one and two children, two and three.
So, I'll just say two nodes, okay, as root is one, okay, and two subtrees, the left one has two in it, so node again, okay?
So, the first one has two here, and that doesn't have any children, because it only has one, two and three.
The other node, the other subtree has three in it, and so that's a algebraic representation of such a tree.
The other tree that we did was, let's copy this one, the other tree is just tree prime, and I will just give it firstly a prime constructor.
This is the tree that has all of the data in the leaves. So, here, the leaf takes an element, and the internal node doesn't have content.
And then again, we want to represent a tree that has one, two, three in this format, in this new, in this new formalism, we say a node, and then we have, it has two subtrees, for example.
And then the first subtree is also a node that has two, one as its children and their leaves, but we need to write each one of them as a leaf.
And the second subtree just as a leaf with three. So, I think I made a mistake with that, because we're not priming, we're not doing prime.
And now, yeah, because we forgot to add a prime there, so that's all for defining datatypes.
Now, in the next video, we'll be talking about how to prove properties about functions that take these arbitrary algebraic datatypes.
So, talk to you there.